# 据说这是将军菜是吧 将军排骨
The dish is called the general’s ribs.
# 你看整个沾上粉子
We coat the ribs well
# 它炸出来就是酥香酥香的
It will be so crispy with aroma after frying
# 必须得裹匀了它
The coat must be even
# 你闻这香味 太有食欲了
Smell the aroma, so appetizing
# 将军排骨辅料：香脆椒，原味小麻花，郫县豆瓣酱，椒盐花生米，泡辣椒，芽菜，红曲米
Ingredients: chilis, fried dough twists, Pixian doubanjiang (bean paste), peanuts, pickled chilis, preserved mustard greens, fermented red rice
# 先把排骨焯了 小魏加点酒 料酒
Let's blanch the ribs first.  Xiao Wei, add some cooking wine
# 这个排骨我跟你讲 最好是什么
For this dish, it is better
# 拿水泡一下 把血水拔拔
to soak them in water first. It helps to get rid off the blood.
# 这样还可以去腥味
and to get rid of the unpleasant flavor.
# 然后这个焯透了就行了
Boil until they are cooked
# 其实通过气味的变化
You can tell from the smell
# (腥味)还是出不去 缺少香料的味
(The unpleasant flavor) is still there. Lack of the spices.
# 比如做蒜泥白肉 或者做酸菜白肉
For dishes like the Sliced Pork Belly with Garlic Sauce and the pork with pickled cabbage
# 人说这酸菜白肉不能吃料香味
Some think you should not taste the spice in the pork with pickled cabbage,
# 但是我提前就搁一大料
but I would put a star anise.
# 这大料我在三分之一的时间
About one third of the boiling time
# 我把大料就择出去了
I take the star anise out
# 然后再往下炖它就没有大料味了
So that the star anise flavor will not be strong
# 但是这种料香气味直接就进去了
But the aroma of the star anise goes into the ribs
# 它没有任何料味
It doesn’t have any taste of the spices
# 所以说这就是一个窍门
That’s a trick
# 该煸锅了吧
It’s time to sauté the herbs
# 葱姜 整料就进去了
Drop big chunks of green onions and gingers in the wok
# 亮子给点豆瓣酱 小魏你攉拢着
Liang zi, put some doubanjiang in. Xiao Wei, keep stirring the wok
# 让它煸 煸香了它 煸酥了它
Stir fry them well to get the aroma out and the herbs crispy
# 泡椒也是整个
Drop the whole pickled chili
# 小魏你看 香气出来了吧
Xiao Wei, see, you can smell the aroma
# 料酒 小亮 搁
Xiao Liang, add cooking wine
# 小亮可以搁水了
Xiao Liang, time to add water
# 可以搁没事儿 红红火火
It’s fine. Looks great!
# 咱们弄点红曲水 搁进去吧
Let's add some sauce from the red yeast rice in the wok
# 你看这颜色更红
See, the color is more red
# 调味吧
Then let’s season the dish
# 加点糖
Some sugar
# （白）胡椒粉
(White) Pepper
# 再搁点酱油
Some soy sauce
# 别搁太多因为这颜色就够了
Don't put too much because the color is (dark) enough
# 这就起一调味作用
Only for the flavor
# 把这个肉捞出来搁这里边
Get the ribs out and drop in the seasoned soup
# 给它挑出来 炖上
Drop and stew the ribs
# 香叶 桂皮 大料瓣 小火炖着吧
Add some bay leaves, cinnamon and star anise pieces, and stew them with low heat.
# 你看这颜色多漂亮 多红亮
Look at the color. So bright and red
# 你看搁点香料这味儿立马就变了
The spices changed the flavor right away
# 肉香味儿出来
The aroma of the pork comes out
# 过去你看湘菜红煨
You see, in the past, for the Hunan style simmering
# 你看蒜不能煸 不能吃出蒜味
We should fry the garlic first, we want the garlic flavor to be subtle.
# 搁了蒜子以外 咱们现在搁一把尖椒
Besides the garlic, we now also put some pepper in the wok
# 就有一种特殊的蔬菜味
It will add some vegetable smell in the dish
# 尖椒是鲜的还是干的 鲜的啊
Fresh or dried pepper? Fresh ones
# 所以说这个肉单独的
What the peppers do to the ribs
# 就有一种特殊的香味
Is to add another dimension of aroma
# 有一种清香气
Makes it more fresh and light
# 你看咱这颜色 加了红曲米的颜色
Look at the color of the dish. It is the color with the red yeast rice
# 看这汤 清澈 红红的
The soup is clear and red
# 排骨的颜色也很自然
The color of the ribs are natural
# 这个炖出来我们可以直接就吃了
We can eat the ribs directly after stewing
# 辣椒 花椒 哗一呲 上边顶着
Or put some chili and Sichuan peppercorn and split the hot oil on top
# 小魏怎么样 又是一道菜
How about that, Xiao Wei? Another dish
# 方法是一样的 就看你怎么去做了
The method are the same, it just depends how you want to cook them
# 这样咱就炖它一会
Let’s stew the ribs
# 实际上通过您这一道菜
Through this dish
# 我能联想起很多菜
I can remind of many different dishes
# 就这个菜的做法可以延展很宽
The recipe of this dish can have many variations
# 排骨啊 你看炖熟了
Now the ribs are ready
# 你看这个颜色是吧 挑出来就行了
The color is so good. Get the ribs out
# 烂烂乎乎 关键是味道 烂是一方面
The texture is very soft, but the taste is the highlight.
# 我把您这个做法学会了
After I learnt your way to cook these ribs
# 回去我拿羊排做去 羊排做也好吃
I can try with lamb. I believe it’s good too.
# 没毛病 拍粉子吧师父
Alright, let’s coat the ribs, Master
# （红薯淀粉）
Sweet potato starch
# 你看整个沾上粉子
Coat the ribs well
# 它炸出来就是酥香酥香的
After frying, it will be delicious and crispy
# 必须得裹匀了它
The key is to make the coating even
# 你看裹不匀就不行
unevenly coated will not be good.
# 要不然炸出来就柴 必须得全裹透了
It will make the ribs dry, We have to coat them all.
# 这边粉子浮着呢师父
Another missing spot here, Master
# 非常香 这已经就炖的很香了
The smell is so good. It is already flavorful after the stewing.
# 油温可以了
The oil is ready
# 咱们做的有点多 多来点吧
We have a large portion here. No problem with big portion.
# 这就差不多
It’s about right
# 哄一下油 让它更加酥脆 外酥里嫩
Heat up the oil and re-fry, so that the coat will be extra crispy
# 出锅喽
Get the ribs out!
# 来点油
Some oil in the wok
# 芽菜 这儿呢 芽菜
Where’s the preserved mustard green? Here. Put in the pan
# 芽菜必须得洗一下啊
Make sure you rinse the preserved mustard green first
# 你看料酒
Some cooking wine in the wok
# 芽菜香了
I can smell the preserved mustard green
# 排骨 搁辣椒
Drop the ribs and chili
# 花生倒么 花生倒 麻花都搁进去
Peanuts now? Yeah, peanuts, and Ma Hua (fried dough twists)
# 小魏 麻辣鲜露
Some spicy seasoning sauce in the wok
# 你闻这香味 小魏 太有食欲了
Can you smell the aroma, Xiao Wei? It is so appetizing
# 你看这上边 麻花
The dough twists looks really nice in the dish
# 排骨做好了师父 将军排骨
The general’s ribs is ready!
# 咱就武吃呗 我也来一块
I can’t wait for the chopsticks. Let me try one first
# 味道非常特殊
The taste is phenomenal
# 外边焦的 里边嫩的
It’s crispy on the exterior but still tender inside
# 这还有一种特殊气味
There’s also a special aroma
# 回口特别好吃 有点麻味儿吧
The taste stays in your month, a little bit numbing too
# 师父您也吃一块
Have a piece,  Master
# 好吃 真好吃师父
It’s really good
# 这是酒菜 要喝酒的话绝了
The dish goes great with some alcohol. It will be amazing if you have this with a drink.